POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY IS THE SCIENTIFIC
STUDY OF WHAT MAKES LIFE
MOST WORTH LIVING.
IT IS A SCIENCE,
AND SCIENCE REQUIRES TESTING THEORIES
AGAINST EVIDENCE.
IT IS NOT A SEQUEL
TO THE SECRET,
AND SHOULD NOT BE CONFUSED
WITH UNTESTED SELF-HELP,
FLY-BY-NIGHT MOTIVATIONAL SPEAKERS,
OR NEW-AGE PHILOSOPHY.
MUCH OF PSYCHOLOGY HAS BEEN
CONCERNED WITH ANSWERING THE QUESTION,
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
IT HAS SOUGHT TO MAKE
INDIVIDUALS LESS MISERABLE,
TO TREAT PATHOLOGY AND MENTAL
ILLNESS.
THE GOAL OF THE POSITIVE
PSYCHOLOGY MOVEMENT IS
TO MAKE NORMAL LIFE MORE
FULFILLING.
IT ASKS THE QUESTION,
WHAT IS RIGHT WITH YOU?
INSTEAD OF TRYING TO HELP
A PATIENT GO FROM MINUS
EIGHT BACK TO ZERO,
THE GOAL IS TO HELP
INDIVIDUALS MOVE UP THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE SCALE.
THE FIELD IS INTENDED TO
COMPLEMENT,
NOT REPLACE,
TRADITIONAL PSYCHOLOGY.
IT
DOES NOT SEEK TO DENY
THE IMPORTANCE OF STUDYING HOW
THINGS GO WRONG,
BUT IT DOES ASSERT
THAT STRENGTH IS AS IMPORTANT
AS WEAKNESS,
AND THAT IT IS JUST
AS IMPORTANT TO BUILD ON
THE BEST THINGS IN LIFE
AS TO REPAIR THE WORST.
POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY IS CONCERNED WITH
INCREASING WELL-BEING.
IS WELL-BEING
THE SAME THING AS HAPPINESS?
NOT EXACTLY.
MARTIN SELIGMAN,
CO-FOUNDER OF THE POSITIVE
PSYCHOLOGY MOVEMENT,
DESCRIBES WELL-BEING AS BEING MADE
UP OF FIVE PILLARS,
POSITIVE EMOTION,
ENGAGEMENT,
RELATIONSHIPS,
MEANING,
AND ACCOMPLISHMENT.
BRANCHES OF EXPLORATION IN POSITIVE
PSYCHOLOGY THE
TERM FLOW WAS COINED BY
MIKE CSIKSZENTMIHALYI,
CO-FOUNDER OF THE POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY
MOVEMENT.
FLOW IS A STATE OF
ABSORPTION IN ONE'S WORK.
IT IS CHARACTERIZED BY INTENSE
CONCENTRATION,
LOSS OF SELF-AWARENESS,
A FEELING OF BEING PERFECTLY
CHALLENGED,
NEITHER BORED NOR OVERWHELMED,
AND
AND A SENSE THAT TIME
IS FLYING.
FLOW IS AN INTRINSICALLY REWARDING
EXPERIENCE.
CAN ALSO HELP ONE ACHIEVE
A GOAL OR IMPROVE SKILLS
AND
IS HIGHLY RELATED TO CREATIVE
INSIGHT.
MINDFULNESS IS INTENTIONALLY FOCUSED AWARENESS
OF ONE'S IMMEDIATE EXPERIENCE.
THE
EXPERIENCE IS ONE OF MOMENT-BY-MOMENT
ATTENTION TO THOUGHTS,
EMOTIONS,
PHYSICAL SENSATIONS,
AND SURROUNDINGS.
TO PRACTICE MINDFULNESS IS TO
BECOME GROUNDED IN THE PRESENT
MOMENT.
BENEFITS INCLUDE REDUCTION OF STRESS,
ANXIETY,
DEPRESSION,
AND CHRONIC PAIN.
LEARNED OPTIMISM IS THE IDEA
THAT A TALENT FOR JOY
CAN BE CULTIVATED.
THAT SAID,
IT'S IMPORTANT TO NOTE THE
RESEARCH TELLS US THAT THE
PATH TO FULFILLMENT REQUIRES CONSIDERABLE
HARD WORK.
THERE ARE FEW IF ANY
SHORTCUTS TO SUSTAINED HAPPINESS AND
WELL-BEING.
ANYONE WHO SAYS OTHERWISE IS
SELLING SOMETHING.
IT IS CONTRASTED WITH LEARNED
HELPLESSNESS,
WHICH IS WHEN ONE BELIEVES
THAT HE OR SHE HAS
NO CONTROL OVER WHAT OCCURS,
AND THAT EXTERNAL FORCES,
SUCH AS GENETICS OR SOCIAL
CLASS,
ULTIMATELY DICTATE HIS OR HER
ABILITY TO ACCOMPLISH A TASK
OR SUCCEED.
EVIDENCE SUGGESTS THAT WELL-BEING IS
NOT SIMPLY THE RESULT
THE FORTUNATE SPIN OF THE
GENETIC ROULETTE WHEEL.
THERE ARE THINGS THAT PEOPLE
CAN ACTIVELY DO TO LEAD
MORE FULFILLING LIVES.
PROFESSOR HOWARD GARDNER IS LEADING
A LARGE-SCALE EFFORT TO IDENTIFY
INDIVIDUALS AND INSTITUTIONS THAT
EXEMPLIFY GOOD WORK,
WORK THAT IS EXCELLENT IN
QUALITY,
SOCIALLY RESPONSIBLE,
AND MEANINGFUL TO ITS PRACTITIONERS.
THE PROJECT ALSO SEEKS TO
DETERMINE HOW BEST TO INCREASE
THE INCIDENCE OF GOOD WORK
IN OUR SOCIETY.
THE GOOD WORK PROJECT ARGUES
THAT SOCIETY AS A WHOLE
WOULD BE BETTER OFF TO
ENCOURAGE INDIVIDUALS TO
PURSUE EXCELLENCE FOR ITS OWN
SAKE,
TO GRAVITATE TOWARD PROJECTS WHERE
THEY REGULARLY ACHIEVE A SENSE
OF FLOW,
AND TO FIND POSITIONS THAT
WILL HELP THEM ACHIEVE HIGHER
LEVELS OF FULFILLMENT.
IS POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY AN EASY
ANSWER TO ALL OF SOCIETY'S
PROBLEMS?
NO,
LET'S NOT BE NAIVE.
BUT WE MUST ASK OURSELVES,
IF WE APPLIED THE TENETS
OF POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY TO
EDUCATION,
BUSINESS,
AND GOVERNMENT,
IF WE ENCOURAGED INDIVIDUALS AND
COMMUNITIES TO
BUILD ON THEIR STRENGTHS,
IF WE FOCUSED ATTENTION ON
THE PILLARS OF WELL-BEING,
IF WE CHANNELED MORE ENERGY
INTO WHAT MAKES LIFE WORTH
LIVING,
WHAT MIGHT BE POSSIBLE